Guide to the National Education Association-Commissions records, 1918-1982 NEA1002.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- National Commission for the Defense of Democracy, 1922-1982; 1944-1968; Series 6; 38.5 Linear Feet
  - Papers-"2,491,000 Youngsters Aged 13, Today's Challenge to Health and Physical Education", 1939; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 2)
  - Papers-"Abolish Public Schools", August 1952; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 3)
  - Papers-"American Education Under Fire", 1951; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 4)
  - Papers-"American Opinion", May 1982; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 5)
  - Papers-"Analysis of the Article 'Your Child is Their Target'", June 1952; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 6)
  - Papers-"The Attack on American Schools", 1958; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 7)
  - Papers-Bureau of the Census Data, February 1953; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 8)
  - Papers-"Campaign for a People's Peace", circa 1943; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 9)
  - Papers-"Character Training with Special Reference to Universal Military Training", October 1947; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 10)
  - Papers-"A Clear Look at the Crisis in American Public Education", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 11)
  - Papers-"The Climate of Freedom", January 1953; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 12)
  - Papers-Compulsory Military Training-Correspondence, 1947-1948; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 13)
  - Papers-Compulsory Military Training-Statement by Dushane, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 14)
  - Papers-"Congressional Committee Doubts Reliability of CASBO", March 1951; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 15)
  - Papers-"Congressional Investigations into Education, the Attacks on Textbooks", 1953; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 16)
  - Papers-Conscientious Objectors, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 17)
  - Papers-Conscription-Anti-Conscription Mailing List, circa 1946; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 18)
  - Papers-Conscription-Bills in Congress, 1946; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 19)
  - Papers-Conscription-Commission Releases on, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 20)
  - Papers-Conscription-Committee to Oppose, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 21)
  - Papers-Conscription-Correspondence, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 1)
  - Papers-Conscription-Correspondence, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 2)
  - Papers-Conscription-Defense Commission Releases, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 3)
  - Papers-Conscription-NEA Statements, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 4)
  - Papers-Conscription-Official Action of Various Organizations, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 5)
  - Papers-Conscription-Publications, 1947; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 6)
  - Papers-"Controlling Juvenile Delinquency", 1943; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 7)
  - Papers-"The Current Attacks on Public Education, A Fact Sheet", January 1953; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 8)
  - Papers-"Danger on the Right", January 1962; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 9)
  - Papers-"Don't Neglect Our Schools", 1950; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 10)
  - Papers-"Education a National Problem...the Need for Federal Aid", January 1942; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 11)
  - Papers-"Education for a Free Society", June 1944; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 12)
  - Papers-"Employment After the War", August 1943; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 13)
  - Papers-"Employment of Women in the Early Postwar Period", March 1947; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 14)
  - Papers-"Epitaph for Three RRR's", 1968; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 15)
  - Papers-"Estimated Numbers of Full-Time and Part-Time Workers 14-19 Years of Age", October 1944; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 16)
  - Papers-"The Fight on International Cooperation: An Analysis of Current Attacks on the United Nations and UNESCO", 1952; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 17)
  - Papers-"Forum Delegates Academic Freedom", circa 1960; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 18)
  - Papers-"Goals for Children and Youth in the Transition from War to Peace", March 1944; Series 6 (Box 1089, Folder 19)
  - Papers-"Good Business Parallels Good Education", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 1)
  - Papers-"The Hate Campaign Against the UN", 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 2)
  - Papers-"How Libraries and Schools can Resist Censorship", February 1962; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 3)
  - Papers-"The Imperative Needs of Youth", circa 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 4)
  - Papers-"The John Birch Society", March 1961; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 5)
  - Papers-"The John Birch Society", April 1961; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 6)
  - Papers-"Knowledge, the World's Greatest Resource", 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 7)
  - Papers-"The Land We Defend", July 1940; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 8)
  - Papers-"Lobbying and its Influence on Public Schools", 1951; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 9)
  - Papers-"Lobbying and Educators", 1951; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 10)
  - Papers-"Marriage: Changing Institution", October 1971; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 11)
  - Papers-"National Assessment Viewed as the Camel's Nose", September 1965; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 12)
  - Papers-"NEA Defense Commission Handbook", 1959; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 13)
  - Papers-"New Crises for Education" (Platform Measure), January 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 14)
  - Papers-"New Tools for Learning about War and Postwar Problems", November 1943; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 15)
  - Papers-"The Outlook for School Enrollments", March 1953; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 16)
  - Papers-"Paying for the War", November 1942; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 17)
  - Papers-"Peace Action of the National Council for Prevention of War", October 1947; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 18)
  - Papers-"Postwar Conditions and Trends", 1943; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 19)
  - Papers-"Postwar Education in America", September 1945; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 20)
  - Papers-"Post-War Planning in Britain", circa 1942; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 21)
  - Papers-"Problems Confronting Boards of Education", circa 1944; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 22)
  - Papers-"A Procedure for Community Post War Planning", October 1943; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 23)
  - Papers-"Pro-Segregation Groups in the South", January 1957; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 24)
  - Papers-"Protestant Piety and the Right Wing", May 1951; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 25)
  - Papers-"A Proud Record of Loyalty", 1955-1961; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 26)
  - Papers-"The Public and the Schools: Counter-Attack", April 1954; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 27)
  - Papers-"Public Education and the Future of America", January 1955; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 28)
  - Papers-"Public Education at the Crossroads", 1953; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 29)
  - Papers-"The Public School and the American Heritage and a Policy to Preserve Free Public Education", 1951; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 30)
  - Papers-"The Public School Crisis", 1951; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 31)
  - Papers-"The Radical Right and the Rise of the Fundamentalist Minority", April 1962; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 32)
  - Papers-"Reading from the Right", June 1956; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 33)
  - Papers-"The Real Enemies of Public Schools", October 1956; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 34)
  - Papers-"Reply to Congressmen Paul W. Shafer's Report", May 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 35)
  - Papers-"Report from Boston", November 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 36)
  - Papers-"Report on Curtis Publications", May 1952; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 37)
  - Papers-"Review of Ultra-Conservative Political Groups", February 1962; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 38)
  - Papers-"The Rights of Tenure Teachers who are Dismissed Due to School Considerations or Reduced School Enrollments", 1965; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 39)
  - Papers-"Rightist Revival: Who's on the Far Right?", March 1962; Series 6 (Box 1090, Folder 40)
  - Papers-"Save our Schools", September 1952; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 1)
  - Papers-"The Save our Schools Business", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 2)
  - Papers-"Scardale's Battle of the Books", December 1950; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 3)
  - Papers-"The Scardale Story", 1952; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 4)
  - Papers-"A Scholar's Devil Theory", April 1958; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 5)
  - Papers-"Schools that Broke the Color Line", 1954; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 6)
  - Papers-"Statement on the John Birch Society by the Board of Directors of Freedom House", May 1961; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 7)
  - Papers-"They Don't Like", October 1962; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 8)
  - Papers-"This Teacher Should be Fired", May 1963; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 9)
  - Papers-"This We Believe about Education", February 1954; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 10)
  - Papers-"The Threat of the Undereducated", circa 1957; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 11)
  - Papers-"The Town that Surrendered to Hate", March 1955; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 12)
  - Papers-"Treatment of Controversial Issues in the Schools", May 1951; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 13)
  - Papers-"The Treatment of International Agencies in School History Textbooks in the United States", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 14)
  - Papers-"The Truth About our Public Schools", June 1954; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 15)
  - Papers-"Unfair Attacks on Education Generate Renewed Support", 1952; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 16)
  - Papers-"Universal Declaration of Human Rights", December 1948; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 17)
  - Papers-Universal Military Training, 1945-1948; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 18)
  - Papers-"Universal Military Training Means Total, Permanent Control of all our Young Men by a Federal Agency", February 1951; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 19)
  - Papers-"An Unwarranted Attack", June 1952; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 20)
  - Papers-"Wartime Health and Education", 1944; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 21)
  - Papers-"We all Believe in Preparedness, How can it Best be Attained?", November 1944; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 22)
  - Papers-"What Three Billion Dollars Would Buy", February 1946; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 23)
  - Papers-"What to do About 'Dangerous' Textbooks", February 1952; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 24)
  - Papers-"What Education Our Money Buys", October 1943; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 25)
  - Papers-"What Should we do about Unjustified Attacks on Schools", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 26)
  - Papers-"Who's Trying to Ruin our Schools", August 1951; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 27)
  - Papers-"Why Our Public Schools are in Serious Trouble", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 28)
  - Papers-Wisconsin Report (Ball v. McPhee), August 1958; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 29)
  - Papers-"Without Warning", May 1959; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 30)
  - Postwar Conference, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 31)
  - Postwar Conference-Agenda I, circa 1944; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 32)
  - Postwar Conference-Agenda II (Revised), 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1091, Folder 33)
  - Postwar Conferences-Alabama, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 1)
  - Postwar Conferences-Arizona, 1946-1950; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 2)
  - Postwar Conferences-Arkansas, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 3)
  - Postwar Conferences-California [file 1/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 4)
  - Postwar Conferences-California [file 2/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 5)
  - Postwar Conferences-Colorado, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 6)
  - Postwar Conferences-Connecticut, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 7)
  - Postwar Conferences-Delaware, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 8)
  - Postwar Conferences-Early Conferences, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 9)
  - Postwar Conferences-Florida, 1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 10)
  - Postwar Conferences-General Statements, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 11)
  - Postwar Conferences-Georgia, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 12)
  - Postwar Conferences-Idaho, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 13)
  - Postwar Conferences-Illinois, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 14)
  - Postwar Conferences-Indiana, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1092, Folder 15)
  - Postwar Conferences-Invitations, Tickets and Badges, 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 1)
    Contains 3 name badges.
  - Postwar Conferences-Iowa, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 2)
  - Postwar Conferences-Kansas [file 1/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 3)
  - Postwar Conferences-Kansas [file 2/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 4)
  - Postwar Conferences-Kentucky, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 5)
  - Postwar Conferences-Louisiana, 1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 6)
  - Postwar Conferences-Maine, 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 7)
  - Postwar Conferences-Maryland, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 8)
  - Postwar Conferences-Massachusetts, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 9)
  - Postwar Conferences-Michigan, 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 10)
  - Postwar Conferences-Minnesota, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 11)
  - Postwar Conferences-Mississippi, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 12)
  - Postwar Conferences-Missouri, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 13)
  - Postwar Conferences-Montana, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 14)
  - Postwar Conferences-Nebraska, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 15)
  - Postwar Conferences-Nevada, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 16)
  - Postwar Conferences-New Hampshire, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1093, Folder 17)
  - Postwar Conferences-New Jersey, 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 1)
  - Postwar Conferences-New Mexico, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 2)
  - Postwar Conferences-New York, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 3)
  - Postwar Conferences-North Carolina, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 4)
  - Postwar Conferences-North Dakota, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 5)
  - Postwar Conferences-Ohio, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 6)
  - Postwar Conferences-Oklahoma, 1946; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 7)
  - Postwar Conferences-Oregon, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 8)
  - Postwar Conferences-Pennsylvania, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 9)
  - Postwar Conferences-Postwar Problems, 1941-1943; Series 6 (Box 1094, Folder 10)
  - Postwar Conferences-Rhode Island, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 1)
  - Postwar Conferences-South Carolina [file 1/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 2)
  - Postwar Conferences-South Carolina [file 2/2], 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 3)
  - Postwar Conferences-South Dakota, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 4)
  - Postwar Conferences-Tennessee, 1942-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 5)
  - Postwar Conferences-Texas, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 6)
  - Postwar Conferences-Utah, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1095, Folder 7)
  - Postwar Conferences-Vermont, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 1)
  - Postwar Conferences-Virginia, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 2)
  - Postwar Conferences-Washington, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 3)
  - Postwar Conferences-West Virginia, 1944-1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 4)
  - Postwar Conferences-Wisconsin, 1945-1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 5)
  - Postwar Conferences-Wyoming [file 1/2], 1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 6)
  - Postwar Conferences-Wyoming [file 2/2], 1946; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 7)
  - "Postwar Problems and Education" [file 1/2], 1945; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 8)
  - "Postwar Problems and Education" [file 2/2], 1945; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 9)
  - Postwar Problems and Education Conference Series, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 10)
  - Professional Problems Committee, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1096, Folder 11)
  - Public Education in a Dangerous Era Conference Reports and Programs, circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 1)
  - Purposes of NEA Professional Rights and Responsibilities, December 1964; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 2)
  - Rawls, Leila, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 3)
    Rawls, Leila
  - Reception for New and Retiring Members, February 1968; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 4)
  - Recommendations of Workshop Conference on NEA Defense Committee Investigations, May 1958; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 5)
  - Reid, Robert H., 1956; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 6)
    Reid, Robert H.
  - Report to the Chairman to the Board of Directors, June 1959; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 7)
  - Report to the First Regional Conference: Democracy Through Education, January 1950; series 6 (Box 4312, Folder 13)
  - Reports-H.R. 1988, 80th Congress, February 1947; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 8)
  - Reports-H.R. 4278, 80th Congress, July 1947; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 9)
  - Saint Louis Convention, 1959; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 10)
  - Sapp, Frances Fell, 1964; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 11)
    Sapp, Frances Fell
  - School Finance Conference, 1942; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 12)
  - School Pictures, 1961; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 13)
  - Schools in the Story of Culture, 1934; Series 6 (Box 4049, Folder 2)
  - Segregation, 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 14)
  - Shull, Martha, 1956; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 15)
    Shull, Martha A.
  - Sources of Instructional Materials on Negroes, January 1946; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 10)
  - Special Legislative Conference, 1961; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 16)
  - Stand By Your Schools, undated; Series 6 (Box 4049, Folder 3)
  - State of the Nation Bulletins (Nos. 1-7), 1955-1970; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 17)
  - Stewardship Report, circa 1961; series 6 (Box 4312, Folder 14)
  - Studies-"Does the Teaching Profession Need a Stronger Defense Commission?", June 1953; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 18)
  - Studies-"Keeping Our Schools Free", 1953; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 19)
  - Studies-"Lets Put First Things First to Make America Strong", 1948; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 20)
  - Studies-"Public Education in a Dangerous Era", 1953-1954; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 21)
  - Studies-"The Responsibility of the Free Mind", 1954; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 22)
  - Studies-"Sources of Instructional Materials on Negroes", January 1946; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 23)
  - Studies-"Stewardship Report of the Defense Commission", circa 1961; Series 6 (Box 1097, Folder 24)
  - Studies-"Study of the National Commission for the Defense of Democracy Through Education", 1958; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 1)
  - Studies-"Survey of Teacher Unions in the U.S., 1956-1957", Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 2)
  - Studies-"True Faith and Allegiance", 1950; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 3)
  - Survey of Teacher Unions in U.S. 1956-57, 1957; series 6 (Box 4203, Folder 3)
  - Survey of Teacher Unions in U.S. 1956-1957, December 1957; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 11)
  - Taking the Grief Out of Grievances in Public School Systems, 1961; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 12)
  - Teacher's Welfare Sessions (Portland, OR), 1956; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 4)
  - Tolerance Conference (NYC), 1945; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 5)
  - True Faith and Allegiance, 1950; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 13)
  - Universal Military Training, 1947-1952; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 6)
  - Washington International Center, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 7)
  - Wiltse, Earle W., 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 8)
    Wiltse, Earle W.
  - Winter, Ruth, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 9)
    Winter, Ruth
  - Workshop Conference on NEA Defense Commission Investigations, 1958; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 10)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Conference on Equality of Educational Opportunity", May 1965; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 11)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"The Conference on Freedom to Learn", April 1955; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 12)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-Defense Commission Workshop-Clinic (University of New Mexico), February 1959; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 13)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Joint Conference on Guidelines for Professional Practice Regulations", December 1961; Series 6 (Box 1098, Folder 14)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Joint Conference, Public Education in a Dangerous Era", May 1953-November 1954; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 1)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Material for use at Conferences Dealing with the Drafting of a Teacher Tenure Act", May 1971; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 2)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Open Meeting", June 1954; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 3)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-Oregon Education Association-National Education Association Leadership Workshop, August 1949; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 4)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-Oregon Education Association-National Education Association Workshop-Clinic, October 1959; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 5)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Proceedings of a Conference on Freedom of Communications", February 1956; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 6)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Proceedings, Conference on Professional Rights and Responsibilities of Teachers in Relation to Newer Educational Media", 1962; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 7)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Report of First National Seminar on Professional Rights and Responsibilities", June 1967; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 8)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Sixteenth Annual Conference on the Critics and the Schools", January 1965; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 9)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Standards for the Conduct of Investigations", 1969; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 10)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Workshop-Clinic on Professional Rights and Responsibilities", January 1962; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 11)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Workshop-Clinic on Solving Conflicts in Education", April 1961; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 12)
  - Workshop and Conference Reports-"Workshop on Personnel Policies", February 1961; Series 6 (Box 1099, Folder 13)
  - Exhibitors AASA-NEA, 1962-1963; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 2)
- National Commission on Teacher Education and Professional Standards, 1930-1975; Series 7; 4.5 Linear Feet
  The Representative Assembly, at its 1946 meeting, established the National Commission on Teacher Education and Professional Standards (TEPS). The Commission was set out to develop a program of teacher recruitment, selection, training, certification and advancement of professional standards.
  The Commission encouraged state affiliates to create agencies that mirror the goals of TEPS on a state level, held national conferences, and encouraged high school and college student organizations related to education and teaching.
  The TEPS Commission continued until 1971, when reorganization combined four units into the Division of Instruction and Professional Development.
  "The National Education Association: The Power Base for Education" by Allan M. West, 1980.
  Series contains materials created by the National Commission on Teacher Education and Professional Standards (TEPS). The files include agenda books from meetings, brochures, papers, letters and workshop and conference programs.
  The majority of the records are agendas, reports and programs from various workshops, conferences and programs sponsored or attended by TEPS.
  - Alabama Association of School Administrators (Birmingham, AL), April 1970-May 1970; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 1)
  - "Alert", September 1970-May 1971; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 2)
  - America's Children Deserve Capable Teachers, undated; series 7 (Box 4292, Folder 14)
  - American Association of School Administrators (Atlantic City, NJ), September 1969-February 1970; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report of Activities 1946-1947, circa 1947; series 7 (Box 4292, Folder 15)
  - Annual Report: Summary of Activities, 1947-1948 and Preliminary Plans for 1948-1949, circa 1948; series 7 (Box 4292, Folder 16)
  - Annual Workshop (Ann Arbor, MI), April 1971-June 1971; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 7)
  - Annual Workshop (Ann Arbor, MI)-Facilities, May 1971-June 1971; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 8)
  - Annual Workshop (Ann Arbor, MI)-Materials Conference, 1971; Series 7 (Box 1100, Folder 9)